PHAKHAMON KONGPETCH PROCESS ENGINEER

36/1 Moo.11, Bangmark, Muang, Chumphon, 86000

E-mail: nummon_22_01_33@hotmail.com

Phone: 077-503787, **Mobile Phone:** 098-5155923

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/phakhamon-kongpetch-8676a437

Age: 29

Nationality: Thai

Marital Status: Single

Languages Skills: Thai (Fluent), English (TOEIC: 600)

Hobbies: Running, Photography and Cycling

Date of Availability: Immediately **Expected salary:** 55,000 Baht up or Negotiable

SUMMARY

Process engineer with over 6 years' experience in FEED, EPC, Petrochemical, Refinery, Oil & Gas sectors. Perform process simulations/ calculations including thermal design of exchanges, hydraulic calculations of piping networks and pipelines, equipment sizing of pump tank and vessel, PSV sizing. Developing H&MB, PFD's, P&ID's, MSD's and process equipment / instrument datasheets. To verify and comments for Licensor equipment specifications. An experience in the use of Process Simulation Programs (PROII, HYSYS, PIPENET, AFT Fathom). Proven ability to coordinate process teams.

CAREER OBJECTIVE: To apply for Engineer. Aiming to use both Chemical and Environmental Engineering

skills to achieve the company goals

Experience

Nov 2019 – Present Process Engineer

Company: Wood Group, Thailand

Address: Talaythong Tower, 53 Moo 9, Sukhumvit Road, Thungsukla, Sriracha, Chonburi, 20230

Work on Lenzing T3 Project

• Perform Hydraulic calculations and Equipment datasheets

Feb 2019 – Oct 2019 Process Engineer (9 months)

Company: Wood Group, Singapore

Address: 991E Alexandra Rd, #01-2, Singapore 119973

Support work to ExxonMobil for CRISP project (Upgrade Chemical and Refinery High Sulfur Fuel Oil to higher value clean products)

- Preliminary PFD / P&ID development
- Line List review and preliminary update / mark-up
- Preliminary line sizing and hydraulic calculation checks
- Pump Data sheet
- Rating of existing lines (review of existing inspection reports)
- Ensure Contractor / Vendors have a working understanding of Project Specifications; Interpret / clarify as needed

Apr 2013 – Jan 2019 Process Engineer (5 years +)

Company: Amec Foster Wheeler Thailand, Ltd.

Address: Talaythong Tower, 53 Moo 9, Sukhumvit Road, Thungsukla, Sriracha, Chonburi, 20230

I have done with rich experience and had executed projects with clients like PTT Global Chemical Public Co. Ltd, Bangchak Petroleum Public Company Limited, S-OIL Company (South Korea), Dung Quat (Vietnam), Thai Petroleum Pipeline Co. Ltd and IRPC.

- Experience in Process and utilities systems.
- Experience in the use of Process Simulation Programs (PROII, ASPEN HYSYS, and AFT FATHOM).
- Perform process simulations/ Hydraulic calculations (Pump, Tank, and vessel).
- Perform piping, equipment and instruments (control valves and PSV) selection.
- Prepare equipment and instrument datasheets.
- Experience in developing H&MB, PFD's, P&ID's, MSD's.
- Prepare line list and tie-in list.
- Prepare process equipment list and deliverable.
- Review major Technical Document provided by EPC and return comments.
- HAZop / SIL experience (attendee).
- Go to site visits and prepare reports.

Mar 2011 - May 2011 Project Engineer (Student internship) Company: Chevron Thailand Exploration and Production, Ltd

Address: Tower III, SCB Park Plaza, 19 Ratchadapisek Road, Chatuchak, Bangkok, 10900

- Hydraulic Calculation of water injection flow during Funan platform shutdown.
- Sizing pipe from separator to depleted well.
- Offshore experience

Education

Jul 2015 - Jul 2017 King Mongkut's University of Technology Thonburi

- Master Degree of Engineering, Major Environmental Engineering
- GPA. 3.95

Jun 2008- Oct 2011 Prince of Songkla University

- Bachelor Degree of Engineering, Major Chemical Engineering
- GPA. 3.18

Courses

- Safety, Health, and Environment NPC Safety and Environmental Service Co., Ltd.
- Basic Offshore safety Introduction. (BOSI)
 Chevron Thailand Exploration and Production, Ltd.

References

Mrs. Kessaraporn Thaopant, Senior Structural Designer, Wood Group Thailand, Ltd. Phone: 081-940-1549